Alright in this video after we talked about the idea of a class and an object, time to implement
those concepts because, uh, imperative you have a good understanding how we implement them,
how we use them, different ways of using them because, because you will be using them
every single day in your life as a Java developer.
So you're back into a playground that is intelligent and we're just going to quickly go on
and just replicate that idea, what I drew for you in the previous video in real, in Java.
So I'm just going to create a new class again and let me just call it class object
Tim, right, because we're demonstrating how do we work with classes and objects in Java.
So I'm going to use the main method again and just to replicate that idea, just to make
you feel related to what we did in the previous video, we're just going to take that idea
forward of the class human and just do it for real in Java in intelligence.
So I'm just going to create the class human as I told you, if now you would have to define
it in Java terms, this is how it would like, just to give you a rough idea.
So class human and I'll say, for example, in legs and you'll say, let's say, uh, long,
uh, for example, arms, that's a two variables for now.
And then we're going to have some methods, some functions, more on variables, we're going
to revisit variables in a different video, we're going to come to methods from scratch
for you, because remember, I'm laying laying out the foundations, very strong and solid
foundations for you to take on the advanced concepts later on with that much ease, right?
So white, but for now, let's put in the method, I'll just say white, uh, white, now let's
say, walk and just an sample sound message, I'll say, humans walk this, right, humans
walk method.
Similarly, I'm going to say, wide eight, how humans would eat, you'll put that idea here,
right, inside class human, this is just the idea that we are defining currently, right?
So it's a humans eat.
Similarly, just one more method there to make you understand the concept, and I'll say,
white sleep, again, in a sound message, I'll say, how do humans sleep, I'll have that defined
here, right, a single class with some variables and some methods, as I said, these are what
we call as data, and this is core, which operates on data.
Right, now, this is just an idea until you create its object, it won't make much sense.
It would make little sense, but not much until you have its physical implementation.
And how do we do that in Java, a few ways to do that?
The first one is just say the type of this time, again, I'm not saying data type because
as I told you in a later video, uh, we would have more types, and this is the right place
to understand that. Now, type cannot just be data types, but a class name as well, right?
So the syntax goes like you say, identify and the new and then type, and the two circular braces,
that's the syntax for creating a new object in Java. Now, this type is, and this identifier is,
what are we trying to name this identifier? What is this identifier for? This is for what we call
as a reference variable. Now, revisiting variables are quickly here. There are two types of variables
in Java. First are primitive type variables, or we can just call them primitive types,
and the second one is reference type variables or just reference variables. Now, which are primitive
types, which have the data type as being from one of those eight primitive types that I told you
that is either a Boolean, a byte, shot, care, int, log, or flow to double, right? If that is, uh,
the data type or the type of a variable, it becomes a primitive type variable, but the type,
if it is not from among those eight primitive variables, data types, then it is a reference type
variable. And what is a reference variable in Java, which can refer to an actual object in memory?
Again, I'll reiterate for you, our reference variable in Java is which can hook or which can point
to or which can refer to the actual object in memory, not a normal constant value that you give
for your primitive variables. And that is why I say type, identifier becomes the identifier for
that reference variable. And then the keyword new, because the keyword new is used to create a new
object in Java at all times, there will be certain situations where you will find an object being
created without even using the keyword new, right? I'll walk you through those, but whenever you
see new, know that a new object is created and what type not to the left of it, but to the right
of it, right? And first starters, this type and this type should be the same until in a later
video, we can change them as well. And I'll tell you why at that time, but for now, for getting started,
the left hand set type and the right hand set type should be the same. And this left hand
sent type in this declaration, it's called a reference type and the right hand type, it's called
the object type. And for starters, I'm telling you the reference type and the object type
should be the same, right? But just for now, later on, we'll change that. So,
following the syntax, if you want to create an object of class human, we'll do it with a main,
we can't do much outside of a method or outside of a class. It's Java, remember, strictly type,
most of the things you will do within a method of a class. And main is a method, right? And I'll
just say, calling this syntax, my reference type is human, I'll call it red to new human object
type would be the same at this line, a new object would be created in memory, right? And that
reference, because we want to still reach out to that object after line number seven at eight,
nine or 10 lines, how would we be able to do that once we have a hook and that hook is in our case,
called ref. So, ref would hold that hook. It would point to that object in memory, right? And with
this object, now you have an object of class human, but there are variations here. Again, you could
do it on two lines, that is like this, ref equal, but at line number seven, make new doubts about it,
no objects exist yet of human. This is just a reference variable, we can refer to an object of class
human in the near future, but it is not referring to anything yet at line away, this is where an
object was created with the keyword new, and we put the reference of that object into our
reference variable called ref, right? And now that's why I say never call ref and as an object,
this is a mistake, which I've seen quite widespread in the industry, freshers even experienced
folks out there, make this, but you're not the one who's going to make this mistake, never call
ref as an object, ref is just a reference variable that can refer to an actual object in the memory,
but it's not the object itself. So, just call it what it is, that is a reference variable,
all right? So, two ways to do that, and then you can go ahead and call it all the methods with the
dot operator on it, and see, this just gives you the variables in the methods that are accessible,
I can call arms, I can say two, you can say ref dot, for example, the method work,
right? Let's run this, we should get the output, which you have written inside work,
and you say humans work, right? Similarly, you can call all the other methods, I'll say
ref dot sleep, let's run this. Humans work and human sleep, that's what we had written inside those
methods, right? So, that's how you create an object, and that's how you call the methods in the
variables on it, and you have even one more way to create an object directly saying something like
this, new human. Without the hook, without the reference variable, and that's probably possible,
because I did not say for creating an object in Java, you just need a reference variable,
no, I said you need the key one, that's what we are doing. And in a way, this looks bizarre,
but it is the most efficient way of creating objects in Java. Why do I say so? Because, see,
when you say new human, all right, so you created the object, and after line number 15,
this object in Java is said to be lost. And once an object in Java is lost, we can never get
back, right? It is lost for all times to come, just remember that, right? And why is it lost?
Because how would you call it? It doesn't have a reference, unlike this one, which had a reference
called REF, so you could call it a line number 10 to an 13 as well, but how would you call it?
But still, I say, this is the most efficient way of creating an object in Java. Why? Because it's
like use and throw, you say new human, you say directly it. Let's say you have to create an object,
call a method on it, call a variable, do something, and you're done with it, and you do not want to
hold unnecessary references, right? Because memory in 2026 is more valuable than ever before,
you do not want to call or have references to unnecessary resources, something which you do not
even need. And what does this do? This creates an object, the efficient way without a reference
variable, without any hook, and then calls a method, and it's done because after line number 15,
we can never reach back to it because that object was lost and it was lost for all times to come.
So three ways to create an object in Java, but in reality, just with the keyboard new, but I
told you that is there would be certain situations, where even without the keyboard new,
we're able to create objects in Java, but I'll just brief you through them when we come across
those situations. But for now, this is how we create in the class, this is how we create an object,
and even better, you can create multiple objects of the same class like we did talk about it
in our in our analogy with human. There was just one human idea that came to almighty,
and then billions came in and followed the same idea. And similarly, you can just do it like this,
in this program only, until line number 15, I've created two objects, one, which has the reference
variable, ref, the second doesn't have a reference, but it was created. I can create another one
as well. I'll just call it another rep. This is the third object created when we reach line number
17 and has the same properties as every human shears, right, but has its own personality as well.
So that is how we can go ahead and create different objects again based on the requirements we would
[BLANK_AUDIO]